Summary

Specializes in full stack web application development. Contributes an open source dynamic graph visualization library. Working his way up from Video Game Tester since college, he enjoys collaborating on deeply technical projects. Joshua has been building web apps for the past decade.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer, 2C Processors USA

(Sep 2019 - Jan 2020) 2CP USA is a financial services company in Summerlin, Nevada.

- Maintained, refactored, and introduced new capabilities to high volume, financial record processing system without breaking the build.
- Rewrote model/view/controller layers as appropriate
- Explored Mono.Net as an addition to the company's toolset
- Left over disagreement over severity of Coronavirus

Systems Engineer, Hirschi Masonry

(- Aug 2019) Hirschi Masonry is a construction company in North Las Vegas, Nevada

- Proposed hiring and helped interview a graphic designer to complement our black and white oriented visual aesthetics
- Thought up and secretly prototyped a self hosted version control setup
- Researched cross platform compatible security solutions
- Collaborated with senior IT professional
 - Introduced programming concepts
 - Learned remote tech support
- Automated Drupal installation

Systems Analyst, Hirschi Masonry

(Jun 2018 -)

- Made structural enhancements to MS Office VB Applications
 - Implemented a clickable calendar
- Learned PHP to enhance Drupal installation with custom features
 - Calendar integration
 - Visual Time Off Planner
 - It's an MVC web application
- Assisted with payroll processing
- Crafted reports on Report Server

Links

Personal Website (Jun 2020)

• https://joshuamoore.dev

Guest Chat (Aug 2020)

https://joshuamoore.dev/chat/ Let's talk! You can also use your own matrix compatible chat client and connect to matrix.leudla.net:8448

An encrypted Graph Editor. Optionally connects to RemoteStorage.js account. (Apr 2020)

https://social-cartography.github.io/

Unencrypted notes on a graph. Optionally connects to RemoteStorage.js account. (Jul 2020)

https://social-cartography.github.io/notes/

Box Lang is a tiny language I wrote, and a Jupyter Kernel (Aug 2020)

- https://github.com/box-lang/sample-boxes/blob/main/Sample%20Boxes.ipynb
- https://github.com/box-lang

A Complete Solution to the Eight Queens Problem (Jan 2020 - Sep 2020)

https://joshuamoore.dev/eight-queens/

Education

- Accepted to University of Alaska Fairbanks' Engineering and Mines Program (Fall 2020)
- Accepted to University of Phoenix (Fall 2019)
- Took two classes at University of Nevada, Las Vegas (Fall 2017 Spring 2018)
- Majored in Computer Science & Software Engineering for 4 years at Seattle University (Fall 2006 - Winter 2010)
- North Pole High School, Alaska (Fall 2004 Spring 2006)
- Dientzenhofer Gymnasium Bamberg, Germany (Fall 1992 Fall 2004)

Credentials







(Aug 2020)

In other words, I can build a web app from scratch. My choice of stack is git+MEAN, these days.